Contact

rnmlb2011@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/michael-baumgardner-phd-rn-20a75b86 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Nursing

BLS

ACLS

Languages

Spanish

Certifications

CCRN

CNL

Honors-Awards

Best Nursing Team Award

Nurse Leader - Structural Empowerment

Jonas Scholar

Publications

Spiritual Well-Being: A Concept Analysis

Michael Baumgardner, PhD, RN

Nurse Manager at Sharp Grossmont Hospital San Diego, California

Summary

Experienced nurse with a demonstrated history of working in the hospital & health care industry. Skilled in Medical-Surgical, Palliative Care, Patient Education, Advanced Cardiac Life Support (ACLS), and Patient Safety. Doctorally prepared nurse scientist with research interests that include: informal caregiving, hospice/palliative care, persons with dementia, end of life care decisions.

Experience

Sharp Grossmont Hospital

Nurse Manager

December 2016 - Present (3 years 7 months)

UCSD Health System

RN

2011 - November 2016 (5 years)

Assistant Nurse Manager on progressive care unit with speciality in transplant care

San Diego Hospice and The Institute for Palliative Medicine Spiritual Counselor 2007 - 2011 (4 years)

Provide spiritual care and ritual to enhance meaning at end of life for patients and their families

Roman Catholic Diocese of San Diego

Priest

1995 - 2006 (11 years)

Provided opportunities for spiritual growth within Catholic community.

Education

Hahn School of Nursing and Health Science Doctor of Philosophy - PhD, Nursing Science · (2014 - 2018)

University of San Diego, Hahn School of Nursing
Master's of Science, Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse · (2009 - 2011)

Pontifical Gregorian University

Master's degree, Theology and Religious Vocations · (1991 - 1994)

University of California at Santa Cruz Bachelor's degree, Biology, General · (1985 - 1989)